Travis Moore

Nashville, TN 37215 • 615.775.1693 Moore.TravisA@gmail.com

Data Engineering Manager Profile

Information technology executive with experience leading successful initiatives in business and higher education. Deep understanding of the strategic role of IT in both administration and efficiency of a business. Broad range of expertise including project management, strategic planning, expectation management, business process transformation, database management, data analytics and operations.

Areas of Emphasis

- Leadership and Team Building
- Data Management and Analytics
- Executive Presentation
- Change Management

- Communication
- Agile Coaching
- Business Development
- Data Pipeline Development

Certifications & Skills

- CompTIA A+
- CompTIA Project +
- Axelos ITIL Foundations 4
- SQL
- Tableau and PowerBI

- CIW Site Administrator
- CompTIA Network +
- Python
- Pandas and NumPy

Professional Experience

Western Governors University - Virtual/Remote

Program Manager - Undergraduate Business, 2016-Present

- Work cross-functionally with senior-level stakeholders, internal and external teams, and other managers to ensure synthesis of data and consistency across operational departments
- Conduct root cause analysis to solve core business problems; conceive, design, and deliver reports and analyses to key stakeholders
- Enable effective decision making through retrieval of data from multiple sources allowing for directives that impact critical business initiatives
- Responsible for bi-weekly operational reporting providing visibility to the objectives and performance of the program
- Team consistently scores 20% above target on service interaction surveys

Byrd Group Two – Nashville, TN

Director of Continuous Improvement & HR, 2013-2016

 Responsible for the design and implementation of a new SaaS (Salesforce) platform and inventory tracking system to support sales, marketing, accounting, and operations from lead generation to close of project Travis Moore

 Identified potential risks associated with the IT infrastructure and source solutions to complex problems

- Led project to move in-house servers to cloud-based platform and provided regular maintenance and support of the organization's computer, server, and cloud services including Office 365, Google Business Suite, OS X, Windows, Salesforce and VoIP Services
- Streamlined client and vendor domestic and international shipping services
- Provided internal technical support for 50+ employees
- Led the Human Resources department which supported 50+ full-time employees and 200+ subcontractors

Hal Leonard - Nashville, TN

Regional Account Manager, 2010-2013

- Created and implemented a development program for call center account managers
- Worked closely with team leaders to ensure development metrics were being met for each representative on their team
- Designed new program and product launch training for call center sales representatives for professional development
- Created daily and weekly routines to ensure all metrics were being met including account maintenance, invoicing, and sales quotas

Target Corporation – Nashville, TN

Executive Team Leader, 2007-2010

- Prepared payroll and inventory budgets for multiple departments and analyzed data to forecast future business needs
- Ensured proper documentation for succession planning and corrective action for five retail departments
- Collaborated with other stores across the district to increase food safety awareness and improve
 Department of Health ratings
- Conducted interviews, onboarding, and training for 50+ retail associates in a new store launch

Educational Background

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT

Bachelor of Science in Data Management and Analytics – In progress est. 2021

Indiana Wesleyan University, Marion, IN

Master of Business Administration Human Resources Management

Belmont University, Nashville, TN

Bachelor of Business Administration